## **Rashid Hafez**

Computer Scientist | AGILE Software Developer

Nationality: BRITISH

Address UK: 7 Highfield, Livingston West Lothian EH54 7BQ

Mobile: +44 7864771747

Website/Portfolio: https://www.rashidsportfolio.co.uk

Email: rashid.hafez1@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rashid-hafez-912bb4159/

#### Summary

## I Graduate on 20th June 2019:

Enthusiastic software developer and 3D programmer. I have attained a vast amount of invaluable skills over the years. Parallel programming, concurrency, efficiency and 3d Graphics are aspects which intrigue me the most. I tend to be overly analytical over the things I love to do, such as games and parallel programming, and 3D graphics.

#### Dissertation (See my website for more details):

My dissertation involves researching methods to partition calculations larger than the device's memory capacity onto a Graphics Processing Unit by programming data parallel pipelines in CUDA.

#### Skills

>	CUDA	>	Java
>	C++	>	Bash/Unix
>	C#	>	HTML/CSS
>	Blender	>	Agile Software Dev/SCRUM/XP/ Project Management
>	Unreal Engine	>	Data structures and Algorithms

#### **Educational Qualifications**

#### Honours Computer Systems (BSC) 2015–2018, Heriot Watt University:

**Year 4 (Est 2:1):** 3D Graphics and Animation, Network Security, Game Programming, Rigorous Software Engineering, Networking Applications.

**Year 3 (60%):** Operating Systems and Concurrency (85%), Data communications and Networking(65%), Professional Development (61%)

**Year 2 (61%):** Hardware Software Interaction (77%), Database Management Systems (75%), Interaction Design(76%), Data Structures and Algorithms (59%)

**Year 1 (60%):** Interactive Systems (70%), Software Development 1 (70%), Logic and Proof (64%)

\_\_\_\_\_\_

## **Rashid Hafez**

Computer Scientist | AGILE Software Developer

#### Heriot Watt Foundation Entry Programme for Engineering 2013-2014 (75%):

Entry Maths (76%), Entry Physics (79%), Academic English for Engineering (80%), Approaches to Learning (63%).

#### Sir William Ramsey School (Buckinghamshire) AS Levels 2012–2013 (60%):

Psychology, Business, IT and Media

-----

#### **Dubai British School GCSE 2010-2012:**

Information Technology, English, English Lit., Maths, Chemistry, Biology, Physics, Psychology, Business, Geography.

## **Work Experience**

## Heriot Watt University. https://www.hw.ac.uk/



# Sept 2018 – Present: Assistant Supervisor Software Development – Computer Science Lab

Currently working for Heriot Watt University Computer Science Dept in debugging and assessing student computer programming. Helped in Software Development for various students as well as on the spot problem solving. Computer languages involved included: C, C++, Java, XML

#### **Tables and Chairs**



#### June 2015-September 2015, Sales Advisor:

Responsible for territory sales in Dubai. Grew healthy pipeline of selling chairs and tables, managed to add several new customers to the company.

# **Rashid Hafez**

Computer Scientist | AGILE Software Developer

## **Hobbies and Interests**

- I have a strong passion for programming and visual effects.
- I've worked on programming a game using the Eclipse IDE and Java language
- My colleague and I developed and founded the Graphics Society in Heriot Watt University
- I also have compiled my own Gaming PC from scratch.
- I'm an avid reader with a vivid imagination, because of this I'm also investing time into writing a book, which I one day would like to develop into a game.
- I'm an every day gamer and very much invested in the fighting game community, I attend tournaments and love the competitive scene.
- Bilingual in English and Arabic